reckon.com.au 2016-06-30

# Policies | Reckon

|  | 

On this page you will find a number of important Reckon policies.   
  
---  
  
## Privacy Policy

Reckon is one of Australia’s leading accounting software developers creating business software for accountants and accounting software for businesses. Reckon provides technical support and training services to the end-users of its products and services, which include desktop, hosted and cloud solutions (“the products”).

Reckon is committed to maintaining the privacy and security of your personal information and complying with the obligations under the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) and the applicable Privacy Principles, known as the Australian Privacy Principles on 12 March 2014 ( “the Privacy Principles”). 

This Privacy Policy applies to each of the companies in Reckon Group, being Reckon Limited and its subsidiaries in Australia and overseas such as Advanced Professional Solutions Pty Ltd (“APS”) in Australia and New Zealand , Reckon Docs Pty Ltd, Reckon Billback Pty Ltd and Reckon Sync Technology Pty Ltd, and Reckon New Zealand Pty Ltd.

Please familiarise yourself with our Privacy Policy to understand:

  * the kind of information we collect and hold;
  * how and when we may collect and hold personal information from you; 
  * the purposes for which we collect, hold use and disclose your personal information and what happens if we don’t collect the information;
  * the circumstances where we are likely to disclose information to overseas recipients and in which countries they are located; and 
  * how you can contact us to access or correct personal information which we hold about you or complain about our collection, handling or disclosure of your information.

By using our products, our technical support services, our website and social media tools, such as Reckon Community (“our products and services”) you signify you have read and understood our Privacy Policy.

## Personal Information

Personal information, for the purposes of this policy and as defined by the Privacy Act and Privacy Principles, means “information whether or not an opinion (including information or an opinion forming part of a database), whether true or not, and whether recorded in a material form or not, about a person whose identity is apparent, or can be reasonably ascertained, from the information or opinion.”

## The Collection of Personal Information

### Purpose

We only collect personal information for purposes which relate to our business, functions and activities. Without your personal information, we may not be able to deliver or give you access to our products, or provide you with technical assistance or updates for our products. 

We collect personal information in relation to the:

  * registering or activating products;
  * verifying and authenticating your purchase, initially and then during your period of use of the product, or where you may have changed details of the computer you are using with the product;
  * providing installation key codes, access codes or other related access details;
  * invoicing;
  * refunds and dealing with warranty issues;
  * providing technical support, assistance, consulting services and training;
  * improving our product and service; and
  * generally, to enable us to provide the product and information needed to ensuring you are able to enjoy the maximum benefit of our products.

Where you provide us with personal information about someone else, for example other authorised users of our product(s), employees’ superannuation details, you must have their consent to provide their personal information to us based on this Privacy Policy.

Subject to your consent, whether express, or implied, ie, where the circumstances of the collection and use are in a manner you would reasonably expect us to collect or use your information, we may also collect and use your information to:

  * promote our products to you; 
  * to provide you with more relevant and personalised information to be more relevant to you and your business;
  * use the information to promote products to you of some of our network of associated service providers and product vendors;
  * to de-identify your information, and using the de-identified information:  
o for internal use for the purposes of analytics with regard to use of our products, development, training and demonstration of our products;or   
o for benchmarking and/or or sale to third parties.

## When We Collect Personal Information

We most commonly collect personal information directly from our customers or their authorised representatives. Sometimes we may collect information from a third party or a publically available source, but only if the person has consented to such collection or would otherwise reasonably expect us to collect their personal information in this way, for example, from Reckon Partners from whom you have purchased our product.

In summary, we most commonly collect personal information when you:

  1. Engage in product related activities, such as:

  * when you purchase, register, install or use our products
  * when you use our technical support or consulting services
  * when you participate in Reckon programs, ie Partner Program, Reckon Advantage, become a reseller
  * when you provide us with copies of your database or give us access to your database and systems so that we can provide you with the technical support or consulting services you may have requested.

2\. Engage with us in other ways, such as:

  * in your normal communications with us, when you email, telephone us or give us your business card   
\- attend public functions, events, seminars, roadshows, conferences, training
  * enter competitions  
\- use our website
  * participate in forums, such as Reckon Community or use other social media tools through our website or in relation to our products

**When you purchase and use our products, technical support and join Reckon programs** we may collect information from you:

  * Upon purchasing by you of any of the Reckon products offered through the Reckon website, any Reckon App, Reckon E-Store, Reckon Call Centre, through retail and other sales channels.
  * Upon registration by you of any of the Reckon products offered through the Reckon website, any Reckon App, Reckon E-Store, Reckon Call Centre, through retail and other sales channels, such as the Reckon Partner program.
  * Upon entering an agreement with us for the installation or implementation of our products, for example, Reckon APS practice management modules, or Reckon APS Private Cloud services.
  * Upon the purchasing of upgraded versions or renewal of subscription versions of Reckon products, often in response to our having communicated with you about such upgrades.
  * When you use our products.
  * When you use our website, community forum, blogs, message boards, & social media links from our website.
  * Upon the joining, or renewal, of various Reckon programs, including Reckon Advantage or the Reckon Partner program.
  * Upon seeking to become a Reckon product reseller where stock is provided on credit, we may seek financial details before approving the appointment as a reseller.
  * When you contact us for technical support or, in relation to Reckon APS products you may also contact us for consulting services, whether online, telephone or in person. Please refer to _“Disclosure to overseas recipients outside the Reckon Group”,_ to understand when your personal information may be disclosed to an overseas recipient, when using our technical support or consulting services. 
  * We also collect personal information indirectly from Reckon Partners relating to Reckon products you have purchased through them.

Personal information may also be collected when customers sign up for add-on services provided by third party suppliers such as banking services (eg for bank data downloads), or merchant account, superannuation payment services (using Westpac QuickSuper services), SMS text services, such as Reckon SMS services, share trading services, wealth management, bill payments services and the like.

In these cases personal information may also be passed on to the third party and will be used, disclosed and protected in accordance with the third party’s respective privacy policy. Please also refer to _“Third Party Service Providers”_ about our use of our third party suppliers and _“Disclosure to overseas recipients outside the Reckon Group”_ , to understand when your personal information we collect may be disclosed to an overseas recipient.

**When your contact with us does not relate to a purchased product.**

We also collect information at other times, which do not relate specifically to your purchase or use of our products, as described below:

  * From delegates who attend our roadshows, briefings, seminars, product training and demonstrations, as well as other public events where registration forms and feedback forms are filled out by attendees.
  * From entrants in Reckon competitions, wherever offered, such as via direct mail campaigns, a Reckon website, social media or any other media, at seminars or public events, which may or may not be hosted by Reckon.
  * Upon registering to request information from us on our website or your responses to offers or other marketing campaigns, competitions on our website or direct marketing campaigns.
  * Use of our website, community forum, blogs, message boards, & social media links from our website.

## Information Collected

The information collected from you or your authorised agent directly, would generally comprise name, address, postal address, telephone, fax and e-mail contact details, other authorised users of your product, where applicable, as well as the details of the Reckon product that you use. 

High level information in relation to your business may be also be collected and may include details of your industry or profession, for the purpose of better understanding your business and needs in relation to our product. 

We collect information from you when installing the product and use of your product , ie a file on your hard drive records the date of installation, such as the unique product number of the computer, collected in relation to your use of the software, for example which may include internet protocol address, hardware identification, operating system, application software, peripheral hardware, non-personally identifiable software usage statistics.

In relation to certain products, we may collect and handle the following;

  * _Reckon BankData_ : bank details solely for purpose of providing your authorisation and obtaining relevant approvals from your relevant bank so that you can receive the relevant bank feeds using our products, for example in your applications to authorise bankfeeds;
  * _Reckon SuperLink_ : banking details and your employees’ personal information for the purposes of transmitting the payment instructions using Westpac QuickSuper portal to process the superannuation payments in accordance with your instructions;
  * information held in databases created using our hosted or online products, such as _SyncDirect_ , _Reckon One_ , _Reckon Accounts Hosted_ or _Reckon APS Private Cloud_. The information collected would be collated and de-identified, before being used for benchmarking or sale to third parties.

### Using our website or social media tools

Depending on the type of activity you are engaging in, we may collect information directly and indirectly when you use our website or social media tools. We may also collect unidentifiable information from you relating to the pages you visit etc. See also _“Reckon Website”_ and _“Social Media & Public Forum”_ below. 

Where you have provided your personal details when visiting our website, such as your membership, account or customer details, or registered for an activity, entered transactions you have entered whether paid or free, we may also collect information from you relating to how you use our website, the pages you have viewed, nature of the requests or enquiries you have made etc.

We also use third party service providers to assist us in the collection of this data relating to your use of the website. These service providers may include technology which enables them to also collect other publically available web-based data or other publically available information about you, such as any social media accounts providers on our behalf. Please refer to _"Third Party Service Providers”_ to understand our use of third party suppliers.

### Technical support or consulting services

If you request technical assistance or, in relation to Reckon APS products, consulting services, you may contact us online, telephone or in person. We may require the following information from you in order to provide you the assistance needed:

  * information relating to your problem and our suggested solutions are also recorded by us to assist in better customer relationship management;
  * you may also need to provide copies of your data or grant access to your database, provide password, pin or other access details in order that we may assist you with your problem or inquiry. Where passwords or other access details are provided, we strongly recommend that you update those access details once your issue has been resolved;
  * you may also be required to provide other details for the purposes of identification and verifying authorisations to provide support, such as if you require us to make any changes to your account or settings;
  * information collected from you in relation to technical support or consulting services may be obtained from you online or by telephone, and in the case of consulting services, they may also obtained on or off your premises.

Please also refer to _“Disclosure to overseas recipients outside the Reckon Group”,_ to understand when you may be dealing with one of our technical support or consulting service providers who are physically located outside Australia.

## How we use and handle this information

Where information is collected in relation to the purchase or use of a Reckon product, we use your personal information in the following ways:

  * We collect personal information so that we can communicate with you about the products that you use and efficiently manage and administer all products we provide to you. These communications could relate to software upgrades, feature variations or enhancements, billings any particular issues or problems that have been detected within the software and corrective measures that may be taken, and informing you of other Reckon products, including the availability of specialised, software specific, stationery products, debt recovery services, software training services, share trading services, banking services, seminars relating to associated products such as share trading classes and other types of classes.
  * Identification and revalidation of software end-users assists Reckon in establishing who is legally permitted to use the various Reckon products and therefore assists us in enforcing copyright and intellectual property rights.
  * Product information collected when it is installed or used assists us to regularly revalidate that the product is being used on the correct computer and is not installed on other computers without your authority and outside the terms of our licence.
  * The information we collect from you relating to your use of the products facilitates the provisioning of updates, support, invoicing or online services to you.
  * In the case of Reckon Advantage, the additional questions we ask in relation to your business, which may include details of your industry or, profession, is to assist us in developing a member profile so that future offerings that may be developed for program participants are relevant and appropriately targeted. As part of the Reckon Advantage service we also send correspondence to Advantage members (including by e-mail) containing product related information as well as promotional material. 
  * In the case of Reckon BankData we only collect data from you to enable you to authorise the relevant bank or financial institution to provide the bankfeeds to be provided and imported into your service using the BankData service.
  * In the case of the SuperLink product, we only collect personal information, such as banking details and the personal details of your employees in order to enable SuperLink to transmit the superannuation payments details to Westpac to make the in accordance with your instructions.
  * Aggregated information:  
o We may also aggregate information which does relate to you to help us to monitor and improve the effectiveness of our website and overall communication to you, for example, providing you information and products relating to matters for which you have indicated an interest in your browsing of our website, or participation in our online activities, requesting information from about products, articles, technical support etc.  
o We may also aggregate information which does not relate to you (containing no information identifiable to a specific person) which is collected:  
\- in relation to your purchase and/or use of our products or relating to use of our website, social media and blogs etc, it may sometimes be used for research and analysis purposes by us or contracted service providers for us to better understand statistical trends in industry and product usage; or   
\- from databases created using our online or hosted products, for example in SyncDirect, Reckon One, Reckon Accounts Hosted, Reckon APS Private Cloud relating to various expense or payment trends. This information is first de-identified then may be used for benchmarking and/or for sale to third parties.
  * Financial information:   
o In the case of financial information requested from parties wishing to be resellers and, as such, who are to be provided with Reckon product stock on credit terms, this information is used to perform credit referencing and checking.  
o Where credit card information is provided, we use it solely to check your financial qualifications and/or to collect payment from you.
  * Technical support or consulting  
o Your information will only by used or accessed for:  
\- the purposes of resolving your technical issue with the product; and   
\- in some instances your information may be used or shared with other departments or entities within Reckon Group, for the purposes of improving our product or business; or  
\- your information may be de-identified and used for product development training and the demonstration of our products; and  
\- once your issue has been resolved your information is returned, destroyed or de-idenitified. 
  * Where you might have purchased a product from one of our network of Reckon partners:  
o then the relevant partner will also have your information and they may from time to time contact you for the purpose of renewal of subscriptions based upon our records of whether or not you have renewed;   
o we may at the request of a Reckon partner provide information relating to the status of licences held by people who have purchased a Reckon product from the relevant Reckon partner; and/or  
o we may provide de-identified personal information to our Reckon partners, who may or may not be the partner you purchased a Reckon product for market analysis, eg number of current licences for our products held in specific region etc.
  * To communicate and promote our products and business. 

If the personal information was collected through your other contact with us, ie. not relating to your purchase or use of our product(s), we use your personal information in the following ways:

  * To follow up any enquiries you may have made a regarding our business or products and, because of the circumstances or express instructions from you, we communicate with you about products we understand you have or a likely to have an interest. Most of this communication with you will be by email. In all email communication of this kind with you, you will have the opportunity to opt out of any further emails.
  * To tailor our communication with you to ensure the information and communication you receive from us is relevant to you.
  * To assess and improve the effectiveness of our website and communication with you.
  * To communicate and promote our products and business.

### Direct Marketing

We will only use your personal information for direct marketing where we have obtained your consent, directly or indirectly and in compliance with the Privacy Principles and the _Spam Act 2003 (Cth)._ In the absence of express consent from you, we will only use or disclose the information in a way that you would reasonably expect your personal information to be used in relation to our business and products. For example, if you provide your business card to one of our employees at an event, we may communicate with you about our products or future events, unless you instruct us not to do so. In all our direct marketing to you, you will always have the ability to request us to discontinue sending to you any further of such direct marketing material to you.

If you would prefer not to receive communications from us that do not relate to any products to which you have subscribed or which you have purchased, please contact us as follows: 

_Australia_  
Phone: 1800 RECKON (1800 732 566)   
Fax: (02) 9577 5557   
Email: [privacy@reckon.com](mailto:privacy@reckon.com)

New Zealand  
Ph: 0800 447 292  
Fax: 09 414 3651  
Email [privacy@reckon.com](mailto:privacy@reckon.com)

_Or write to us:  
_

The Privacy Officer  
Reckon Limited  
Locked Bag 7522,   
McMahons Point, NSW 2060 

OR

The Privacy Officer  
Reckon New Zealand Pty Ltd  
PO Box 331 534   
Takapuna, Auckland  
New Zealand

## Disclosure

We will only use the personal information for the purpose for which it was given to us, or for purposes which are directly related to one of our functions or activities. We would only disclose information in circumstances permitted by the Privacy Principles, such as when:

  * You have consented;
  * You would reasonably expect, or have been otherwise made aware, that information of that kind is usually passed to individuals, bodies or agencies;
  * It is otherwise required or authorised by law

Information collected may be shared with other subsidiaries within the Reckon Group for use in the provision and improvement of their products to you and in their advertising and marketing programs. Where information is shared within Reckon Group it will be disclosed and handled in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy. 

Subject to the exceptions below, very little external disclosure of your personal information is made by Reckon outside the Reckon Group:

  * Where an external party wishes to communicate with any or all parts of the Reckon user/Advantage member database, and Reckon is agreeable to this communication being sent, we would generally undertake the communication on behalf of the external party (but at their cost) so that;
  * Information may be provided to third party technical support services located outside Australia, for the purposes of dealing with technical support issues you may have raised to assist you and/or or which may also assist us to improve our product and process generally. Please refer to _“Third Party Service Providers”_ about our use of our third party suppliers and to _“Disclosure to overseas recipients outside the Reckon Group”,_ to understand when your personal information may be disclosed to an overseas recipient
  * If you have signed up for add-on services provided by third party suppliers such as banking services, bank data downloads, superannuation payment services, merchant accounts, SMS text services. In these cases personal information may also be passed on to the third party and will be used, disclosed and protected in accordance with the third party’s respective privacy policy. Please refer to _”Third Party Service Providers”_ about our use of our third party suppliers and _“Disclosure to overseas recipients outside the Reckon Group”_ to understand when your personal information we collect may be disclosed to an overseas recipient;
  * Reckon may use, from time to time, external service providers to facilitate communications with its customers, for example a mail house. In these circumstances, Reckon may provide personal contact/address information to the external service provider to enable the communication to be dispatched. Such information is provided to the external service provider on the strict basis that it be used for this purpose only and that their handling of the personal information provided to them complies with Reckon’s Privacy Policy and the obligations of the Privacy Principles. Agreements with the external providers are put in place to ensure this. Refer to _“Disclosure to overseas recipients outside the Reckon Group”_ for more details;
  * where the information is disclosed to a credit referencing bureau;
  * if required by law or to comply with a law, court order or legal process.

In the event there is a transaction which involves the sale or any or part of our business assets, it is possible that personal information we possess may be transferred as part of the transaction. Further, where reasonably practicable, we will specify that the personal information will be handled in accordance with this policy and consistently with the requirements of the Privacy Principles.

### Disclosure to overseas recipients outside the Reckon Group

In accordance with the provisions of the Privacy Act and Privacy Principles we advise that some personal information may be disclosed to a third party outside Australia. These parties may only use the information for the identified purpose and must use, handle and disclose the information in accordance with this Policy. Please also refer to _"Third Party Service Providers”_ to understand our use of third party suppliers. 

**Circumstances where your information may be collected, disclosed or stored outside Australia:**

_Reckon APS products: Practice Management - on premise & Private Cloud_

  * When purchasing or renewing products or seeking technical support, you may be assisted by our overseas subsidiaries in New Zealand.
  * If you use any of our products which incorporate Microsoft Office 365 ,then your emails and other data created using this software maybe also be stored and/or hosted by Microsoft in Singapore. Please refer to Microsoft’s Privacy Policy in relation to its collection and handling of personal information from users of the Microsoft Office 365 product.

_Reckon Accounts products, Reckon Advantage Membership_

  * When purchasing, registering or renewing products or seeking technical support, you may be assisted by our third party suppliers located in India.

_Virtual Cabinet_

  * When installing and registering the product, personal information may be provided to our overseas subsidiary in the UK in order to obtain the licence key or other access credentials for you to be able to use the product. The portal is hosted on servers in secure data centres in the UK managed by third party suppliers. As a consequence documents accessed using the portal will also be hosted on these servers in the UK.  

 _SMS texting services_

  * Using Reckon SMS services, your customer details are stored by Reckon in Australia. However, Reckon’s third party telecommunications service provider, relies on its global partner network to provide the services, so SMS texts sent using this service may be stored on the third party service provider’s global network.

 _Website use_

  * If you visit our website and provide personal information, we use third party service providers to provide analytics and information relating to your use of our website. 

### Reckon Website

You may explore and browse our website without providing any information about yourself. When you visit our website, for example, to purchase any products, or enrol into a training course, technical support, contribute to a forum, register for an event, participate in a competition or promotion, request further information from us, we generally request that you provide personal information about yourself primarily so that we can respond to your query, provide you with further information, confirm your details, booking etc. 

You may choose not to provide this information but this would prevent or minimise your ability to experience the full features of the website, such as online payments, access to some subscription products, restrict access to certain areas of the website or activities. 

The Reckon website uses: 

  * "cookie" technology. What are cookies? Cookies are pieces of information that a web site transfers to an individual's hard drive for record-keeping purposes. Cookies make web-surfing easier for you by saving your passwords, purchases, and preferences while you're on a website. The use of cookies is an industry standard - you'll find them at most major web sites. You have the ability to accept or decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to experience the full features of the website. 
  * “navigational information”. This is information about your computer and your visits to this website such as your IP address, geographical location, browser type, pages viewed, referral source. We use this information to improve the website. We may combine the navigational information and personal information to provide you with more tailored information about our products and business.

### Social Media & Public Forum

Our website includes social media tools, such as the Facebook Like button, share this button. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our sites, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. The social media tools are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Websites. This Privacy Policy does not apply to these features. Your interactions with these features are governed by the Privacy Policy and other relevant policies of the companies providing them.

We also offer publicly accessible community forums, message boards and blogs. Please be mindful that any information you directly disclose through our public message boards, blogs, or forums, may be collected and used by others. We will correct or delete any information you have posted on the websites if you so request, please refer to _“Access to Information and Complaints”_ section below.

### Third Party Service Providers

We engage third party service providers to provide services to users of our websites and products and may need to share information, or give access to your personal information in order to provide information or products to you. The types of third party services may include analysing data, providing marketing assistance, technical support, consulting and training services relating to the installation, use, development, maintenance and support of our products, Reckon SMS services, providing office and document management services, such as Microsoft Office 365.

We do all things reasonably practicable to select third party service providers, who represent, or who, in our reasonable opinion, we believe will comply with the Privacy Principles in relation to the collection, use, storage , disclosure and security of your personal information consistent with the Privacy Principles and this policy and only use the information for which it is disclosed.

Some of these third party service providers may store or host their data, which may include personal information they have collected on our behalf, outside Australia. Please refer to _“Disclosure to overseas recipients outside the Reckon Group”._

When using our products, you may also access add-on services provided by third party suppliers, which are provided to you subject to the terms of the third party supplier’s terms and conditions. In these circumstances, the collection, use, handling, storage and security in relation to any personal information collected from you by such third party, will be solely governed by the terms of their privacy policy, not Reckon’s Privacy Policy.

### Information held by Third Parties

As a company incorporated in Australia and listed on the Australian Stock Exchange, Reckon is required to maintain a register of members pursuant to the Corporations Law. This function has been contracted to an external provider, Computershare Limited (“CS”). 

It is the usual practice for registers of listed companies to be managed by third parties. CS manages the members' register on behalf of Reckon, which includes personal information relating to name and address details, security-holding balances, tax file numbers, bank account details and e-mail addresses. CS has its own Privacy Statement as to how it deals with personal information, and Reckon shareholders are directed to the Computershare website [www.computershare.com/au](http://www.computershare.com/au) for further information.

The trading and dealing activities of the Reckon ANZ Share Investing service are performed by Share Investing Limited (ABN 93 078 174 973, AFSL No. 238277). Pursuant to the agreement that Reckon has with Share Investing Limited, and as authorised by the customer when agreeing to the trading rules, ANZ Share Investing can provide to Reckon, at Reckon's request, personal information relating to the customer. ANZ Share Investing has its own Privacy Statement and Privacy Policy, and Reckon ANZ Share Investing users are directed to the Reckon ANZ Share Investing section of the Reckon website (<http://estore.reckon.com.au/74/34/ANZ-Share-Investing/more>) for further information.

### Third Party Websites

Our website and products may link to other websites. We do not control and are not responsible for, the content or data collection, handling and storage practices of any of these third party websites. Nor does the provision of any links to those websites constitute an endorsement of these other websites, their content or their practices. We do not have any control over any cookies or any tacking technologies they may apply. 

This Privacy Policy does not apply to third party websites. These other websites are subject to their own privacy and any of their other related policies, if any. 

## Information Storage, Destruction & Security

Reckon is committed to take all reasonable steps to protect all its information, including from misuse, interference and loss and unauthorised access, modification and disclosure.

We require all our employees, contractors and agents to agree to obligations of confidentiality with respect to information collected, handled or held by us or on our behalf, such as personal information and client information. 

Information received by us or on our behalf, from clients or users of our products is treated in accordance with these obligations of confidentiality and the terms of this Privacy Policy.

Reckon uses electronic customer management and database systems to store most of the personal information. Some of the customer management and database systems are web-based. Some of these systems may be provided by third party service providers. Please also refer to _“Third Party Service Providers”_. Our databases and systems are accessed by authorised users and contain security features to ensure the protection and integrity of the data that we hold. 

Reckon data and customer data created using Reckons products is stored on our servers which are kept in secure data centres owned and managed by third parties. Most of this data is hosted and stored in our data centre in Australia. 

We generally return or destroy or de-identify data which has been provided to use for technical support or consulting purposes. Some data, once de-identified, may be kept for training or QA purpose so that we may continue to develop and improve our products and processes.

Some of your personal information may also be in stored in databases hosted by third party service providers, in Australia, US or other countries, please see the relevant paragraphs _“Third Party Service Providers“_ and _“Disclosure to overseas recipients outside the Reckon Group”_ for more details.

## Access to Information and Complaints

The Privacy Principles provide you with the right to access the personal information that we hold in relation to you. If you would like:

i. details of the personal information which we may hold about you; or,   
ii. to correct any of the information that we hold;  
iii. to complain about a bread of the Privacy Act or Privacy Principles, please contact us as follows:  
 __

_Or write to us:_

The Privacy Officer  
Reckon Limited  
Locked Bag 7522,   
McMahons Point, NSW 2060  
Australia

OR

The Privacy Officer  
Reckon New Zealand Pty Ltd  
PO Box 331 534   
Takapuna, Auckland  
New Zealand

We have internal procedures in place to deal with such requests, and we may require further information from you to verify your identity. Generally, we will correct or give access to your personal information where it is reasonable and practicable to do so in accordance with the provisions of the Privacy Principles. If Reckon refuses to correct, or grant access to the personal information on grounds consistent with the Privacy Principles, then Reckon will provide written notice to you of its decision and reasons for the decision in the form required under the Privacy Principles.

## General

Should you have any queries in relation to this Privacy Policy or to issues generally surrounding the personal information that we hold about you, please contact the Privacy Officer at the relevant address referred to below. 

From time to time, this statement may be amended. An up-to-date version of the Privacy Statement will always appear on this page. If we make any material changes we will notify you by means of a notice on this page or notify you by email, at our discretion. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our Privacy Policy. 

Furthermore, you may request a copy of this Statement from either the addresses referred to above or by phoning or emailing:

Australia:   
Ph. 1800 RECKON (1800 732 566)  
Email: [privacy@reckon.com](mailto:privacy@reckon.com)

_Last updated 18 September 2014_

## Anti-Piracy Policy

### What is Piracy?

A number of activities can fall within the term "software piracy" - these activities include illegal copying of programs, counterfeiting and distributing software. Even sharing software between friends or associates can amount to software piracy.

### Piracy Worldwide

A worldwide study launched in 2001 by the Business Software Alliance on business software piracy showed that in 2011:

  * The world piracy rate increased to 42%
  * an estimated US$63.4 billion was lost due to piracy by region, Central & Eastern Europe has the highest piracy rate at 63%
  * Piracy rates in the emerging markets (68%) are significantly greater than in mature markets (24%)

### The impact of software piracy

Put simply - software piracy is a form of theft, and like theft in the conventional sense, it has a flow-on effect to the rest of the community. Software piracy impacts different stakeholders:

  * Consumers, especially those who rely on the software to run their business and/or earn their livelihood are put at risk with the potential of unreliable software which may contain bugs or viruses (and which can impact the network), and such software often lacks key features, documentation or upgrade options
  * The software manufacturer/distributor is economically impacted in a huge way, having borne the large cost of developing what it believes to be a marketable and important business solution, only to have disreputable people and companies undermine its ability to seek a return on this huge investment. The software manufacturer/distributor is the one paying the taxes and providing jobs and wages to a legitimate workforce, and it never receives any funds from the sale of counterfeit software
  * The software industry and the community at large is impacted when the legitimate businesses lose revenue which then leads to layoffs for workers in related industries, from manufacturers to resellers

Knowingly using pirated software can put you or your company at risk.

Many people may think that using pirated software in their business is a way of saving the business money, and that it is unlikely that they will ever be found out. However, the following are risks which need to be considered if pirated software is used, and could result in the business paying far more than the cost of the software:

  * In the event that it is discovered that your business is using pirated software, the fines for infringement of copyright and the consequent legal costs for defending any action can be significant; 
  * In the event that the media picks up on copyright infringement by your business, this can have a significant impact on your business's reputation and how your business is view by others;
  * Because pirated software is an "unknown quantity", it is unsafe to assume that this software will be compatible with other software which you used. Similarly, you will not be able to receive technical support or there is the possibility that pirated software will not be able to be upgraded. For these reasons, your company is at risk of business interruption and down-time.

### Who will ever find out that you are using pirated software?

Whilst it is true that there are no software pirating police out on patrol, don't think that you won't get caught. If you choose to use pirated software, you may be found out in many different ways. If you choose to sell your business at some point in the future, it is likely that the party proposing to buy will, as part of the purchase enquiries, seek to see proof of purchase of the software. Similarly, your accountant may also become privy to your use of pirated software if he/she is engaged to assist you. There are other ways, which for obvious reasons we are unable to disclose, that can alert us to the use of pirated software.

### What will Reckon do if it discovers that pirated software is being used?

Reckon, in conjunction with the intellectual property owner of the QuickBooks software, Intuit Inc., will use the full force of the available law and take all such action as is necessary to prosecute for an infringement of copyright and any other intellectual property rights. Reckon and Intuit Inc. spend many millions of dollars each year in the development of software. For this reason, this asset needs to be strictly protected. The cost of any such legal action taken by Reckon or Intuit Inc. is very small compared with the very large development costs.

### What can you do to look out for pirated software?

If you think you have bought software that it is so cheap, it seems too good to be true, it more than likely is too good to be true. The following may assist in identifying pirated software:

  * Products which do not come with user manuals
  * Products which have no packaging
  * Handwritten labels on CDs or disks
  * Products bought from places any other than a reputable software dealer, such as market stalls

Only buy Reckon software from a reputable software dealer or direct from [Reckon](http://reckon.com.au/) or by telephoning 1300 RECKON (1800 732 566).

## Terms of Use and Disclaimer

### Privacy and Collection Notice

Please also familiarise yourself with our Privacy Policy to understand:

  * the kind of information we collect and hold;
  * how and when we may collect and hold personal information from you;
  * the purposes for which we collect, hold use and disclose your personal information and what happens if we don’t collect the information;
  * the circumstances where we are likely to disclose information to overseas recipients and in which countries they are located; and 
  * how you can contact us to access or correct personal information which we hold about you or complain about our collection, handling or disclosure of your information.

By using our products, our technical support services, our website and social media tools, such as Reckon Community (“our products and services”)  you signify you have read and understood our Privacy Policy which can be found here.

### Trademark

Reckon, R logos, Reckon Online, Online logo, Reckon Accounts, Advantage logo, Reckon Essentials are trademarks of Reckon Limited (“Reckon”). 

### Agreement

By accessing the information, products and services (“the products”) contained in our website you agree to be bound by the terms and conditions of this Agreement. The terms of this Agreement may, from time to time, change. It is your responsibility to re-visit these terms and conditions. By continuing to access the information and products contained in our site you will be taken to have agreed to the terms and conditions prevailing from time to time.

### Products and Services

Use of any of the products are governed by the relevant terms and conditions for the product or service. Except as required by the Australian Consumer Law, Reckon provides the products to you on an "as is" basis and without any representations by Reckon or any of its authorised distributors regarding the use, performance or results of the use, of the products.

### Third Party Products and Online Services

The website and products may contain access to, or features that interface with, third party products and online services ("Third Party Online Services"). Where Third Party Online Services are available, separate terms and conditions with the provider of the Third Party Online Services may apply. Charges may apply for the use of Third Party Online Services including the cost of internet access. Except as required by the Consumer Guarantees, access to Third Party Online Services may be withdrawn by Reckon at any time. Reckon does not make any recommendations in relation to the Third Party Online Services or accept any liability or responsibility for any loss or damage relating to the Third Party Online Services except as required by the Consumer Guarantees.

### Reckon does not provide financial, accounting, taxation, superannuation, wealth management or financial product advice.

The information contained in the website or the products may contain features designed to assist you in complying with the requirements of the relevant legislation. You acknowledge that Reckon is not engaged in rendering legal, accounting or other professional services and nothing in the website or any of the products constitutes taxation, financial, wealth management, superannuation or other professional advice in relation to these matters. The help contained in the Software is not a substitute for obtaining the appropriate independent professional advice. Legal, accounting or other relevant professional advice should be obtained before taking any action in reliance on any of the products or services or what is produced by the or anything on the website the Software or what is produced by you using the Software.

### Reckon has no responsibility for recommendations:

Except as required by the Australian Consumer Law, Reckon, its employees, agents, contractors and the authors disclaim any and all liability and responsibility to any person, whether a user of the website or the products, in respect of anything (including, without limitation, any error in or omission from the website or products) and of the consequences of any actions taken or omitted to be taken in reliance, whether wholly or partially, upon all or any part of the content, recommendations or help contained in this website or the products.

### Corruption of Data and on-line access:

Except as required by the Australian Consumer Law, Reckon and its authorised distributors disclaim all liability for any corruption of data, inability to access data, loss of data, breach of privacy, or downtime as a result of or arising from the use of any online link available between the website or the products and another server including without limitation in connection with any online Services.

### Confidentiality

While Reckon uses its best endeavours to ensure that your information remains confidential (including the use of advanced encryption technology), the internet is not completely secure and there remains a possibility that information you provide could be intercepted by unauthorised persons.

By accessing our site, you accept the terms of our privacy statement, which are incorporated herein.

### Copyright

You agree not to infringe Reckon’s or any third party’s copyright or any other intellectual property rights or common law rights in any of the material on the website or the products, for example you will not copy, down load, re-transmit or disseminate any of the copyrighted material (except where this is expressly permitted by Reckon). You also agree not to infringe any trademark of Reckon or a third party which appears on the Reckon site.

### Advertisers, Sponsors and Links to Other Sites

By accessing the website it may be possible to link to other sites. Reckon is not responsible in any way for the content or information that may be available or accessed via the website is the sole responsibility of the relevant advertiser or sponsor.

Passwords, Access Numbers and Account Numbers

On registration as a user with Reckon for a particular product you may be provided with a confidential password, access number and/or account number. It is your responsibility to keep these confidential and to notify Reckon as soon as you are aware that any of these have been accessed by unauthorised persons. If you give any of these access tools to other persons it is your responsibility for any charges or other liability that may arise from those persons having access.

### Reckon ANZ Share Investing

The Reckon ANZ Share Investing service is provided solely by Share Investing Limited (ABN 93 078 174 973, AFSL No. 238277), of 242 Pitt Street, Sydney NSW 2000, an ASX and Chi-X Australia Participant, under an agreement between Share Investing and Reckon Investment Centre Limited ("RIC"). When referring you to ANZ Share Investing, a portion of the brokerage fees paid by you to ANZ Share Investing will be rebated to RIC as a commission. RIC may receive between 12% to 18% of the brokerage payable to ANZ Share Investing plus a trailing commission. To the extent permitted by the Australian Consumer law: (a) neither RIC or Reckon and its related bodies corporate have any legal liability to you in respect of the Reckon ANZ Share Investing service and the activities and service of Share Investing Limited and its related bodies corporate; and (b) Share Investing Limited and its related bodies corporate have no legal liability to you in respect of the activities and services of RIC or Reckon and its related bodies corporate.

### Traffic flow

Response times and the ability to effect an on-line transaction vary with user demand. You agree not to hold Reckon (or, where applicable, any third party service provider) responsible for any inability to make an on-line transaction to the extent permitted by Australian Consumer Law.

### Obligation to Pay All Relevant Subscription and User Fees

You agree to pay all subscription, service and user fees which may be levied by Reckon for accessing its site or using the products. These charges may be varied from time to time. It is your responsibility to inform yourself of the charges which are applicable from time to time. This may either be done by accessing the information through the website or telephoning Reckon's support service.

### Monitoring of Use of Website

Use of this site may be monitored by Reckon for security or quality control purposes.

### Limitation of liability

This clause is subject the Australian Consumer Law as amended from time to time, or other similar legislation of a state or territory of Australia.

In Australia, our products come with guarantees that cannot be excluded under the Australian Consumer Law. You are entitled to a replacement or refund for a major failure and compensation for any other reasonably foreseeable loss or damage. You are also entitled to have the products repaired or replaced, or service resupplied in the case of a service, if the goods fail to be of acceptable quality and the failure does not amount to a major failure.

To the extent permitted by the Australian Consumer Law Reckon (and any third party service provider): (a) expressly exclude all implied warranties whether as to merchantability, fitness for particular purpose, or otherwise; and (b) exclude all guarantees, conditions, warranties and rights that may be implied into this agreement or imposed by law. 

The liability of Reckon (and, where applicable, a third party service provider such as a bank or financial institution) is limited (at the option of Reckon or the relevant third party service provider) to either providing the service again or paying for the costs of the service to be provided again unless otherwise required by Australian Consumer Law.

Except to the extent required by the Australian Consumer Law, neither Reckon, or where applicable, a third party service provider, shall be liable for any consequential, special, consequential, economic or indirect loss that may be occasioned by you accessing the website or using the products; and Reckon's maximum liability for damages arising in connection with you accessing website or the products.

### Accredited Trainers and Professional Partners

The list of independent parties contained in Support: Training and Accounting Support section of this website is a list of independent parties who have indicated their preparedness to provide after-sales service, in respect of Reckon products Reckon Ltd does not and cannot warrant the services, the quality nor their suitability for the purpose of the services provided by the listed independent parties. It is the sole responsibility of the purchaser to make the appropriate enquires and satisfy themselves as to the quality, suitability and price competitiveness of any party they may subsequently choose to assist with them in the establishment and use of their services.

The use by the independent parties of any of the Reckon trademarks or logos and advertising material should not be construed as the endorsement of quality, suitability or price competitiveness of the service of the independent parties. There is neither a relationship of agency, partnership, joint venture nor any other association between Reckon/ and the independent party. The independent parties pay annual and other fees to Reckon.

### Jurisdiction

You agree that the terms of this Agreement are to be governed by the laws applicable from time to time in the State of New South Wales, Australia.

### Enforceabilty

If for any reason any provision of this Agreement is rendered void or unenforceable at law, then this Agreement is to be read as if that particular term or provision had not been included.

## Reckon Blog Guidelines

We invite you to participate in the community of this page by leaving comments related to a blog post. Your opinions are important to us. We just ask that you follow some guidelines. 

The guidelines for posting comments

  * Comments should relate to what is covered in the blog post.
  * If you post a link, please give us some background; links with no additional information will not be included.
  * Comments that include personal attacks on other people in any way will not be published.
  * It is best not to post any personal information such as your email address or phone number in the comment.
  * Any comments that include language that is obscene, racist, sexist, discriminatory, offensive or otherwise inappropriate will not be published, in Reckon Ltd's absolute discretion.
  * Any comments that are clearly being made to sell products, solicit money, or recruit members to another forum will not be published.
  * Any comments containing information considered to be misleading or unlawful will not be published.
  * Reckon Ltd reserves the right to remove any comment which Reckon in its absolute discretion considers to be outside of these Guidelines, in breach of any law or regulations, offensive or inappropriate.

Please note this blog is moderated and comments are subject to moderation before being published. 

If you have any comments on these guidelines, something you think should be included or something that shouldn’t, let us know by emailing [socialmedia@reckon.com.au](mailto:socialmedia@reckon.com.au?subject=Reckon%20Blog%20-%20Online%20Enquiry)

**Disclaimer**  

Comments posted to the Reckon Blog do not represent the opinions of Reckon Ltd. The Reckon Blog is intended to provide a place for discussion on topics related to Reckon's products and services.

**Blog contributor guidelines**

Reckon Accredited Partners are invited to participate in the Reckon Blog by providing posts for consideration. Your opinions are important to us, we just ask that you follow some guidelines.

The guidelines for blog posts:

  * The Reckon Blog Book provides broad guidelines on purpose of the blog, tone of voice and the submission process. Please review this before submitting a blog post for consideration. A copy of The Blog Book can be obtained by contacting [socialmedia@reckon.com.au](mailto:socialmedia@reckon.com.au).
  * Posts should relate to issues, trends, topics related to small to medium sized businesses and/or accounting professionals in Australia.
  * Include links, but please check them first. If you include a link in your post please give us some background.
  * Comments that include personal attacks on other people in any way will not be published.
  * It is best not to post any personal information such as your email address or phone number in the post. It is ok to link back to important information related to the post but it must have context.
  * Any posts that include language that is obscene, racist, sexist, discriminatory, offensive or otherwise inappropriate will not be published, in Reckon's absolute discretion.
  * Any posts that are clearly written to sell non-Reckon related products or services, solicit money, or recruit members to another forum will not be published.
  * Any posts containing information considered to be misleading or unlawful will not be published.
  * Reckon reserves the right to remove any posts or comments which Reckon in its absolute discretion considers to be outside of these Guidelines, in breach of any law or regulations, offensive or inappropriate.

Please note this blog is moderated and comments are subject to moderation before being published.

If you have any comments on these guidelines, something you think should be included or something that shouldn’t, let us know by emailing [socialmedia@reckon.com.au](mailto:socialmedia@reckon.com.au) 

**Disclaimer**

Blog posts authored by Reckon partners do not represent the opinions of Reckon Limited. The Reckon Blog is intended to provide a place for discussion on topics related to Reckon's products and services.

## Website Terms of Use

### Agreement

By accessing and using the website, including participation in any of the discussion forums, such as Reckon Community, message boards or blogs, registrations for events, training etc, purchases, or accessing the information, products and services (collectively “the products”) contained in our website, you agree to be bound by the terms and conditions of this Agreement. 

_If you do not accept these terms and conditions_ , you must refrain from using this website.

The terms of this Agreement may, from time to time, change. It is your responsibility to re-visit these terms and conditions. By continuing to access the information and products contained in our site you will be taken to have agreed to the terms and conditions.

In these terms and conditions, the terms "we", "us" and "our" are a reference to Reckon Limited and its subsidiaries.

### Data Collection and Privacy

Reckon collects personal information from you when you access or use the website, discussion forums and any products.  The terms under which Reckon collects, uses, handles and discloses personal information is as set out in Reckon’s Privacy Policy which can view on the website.

By using the website you consent to the terms of Reckon’s Privacy Policy.

_If you do not agree_ _to the terms of Reckon’s Privacy Policy_ you must refrain from using this website.

### Monitoring use of the website

The website uses cookie technology and navigational information. Reckon may monitor and track your use of the website in accordance with the terms of Reckon’s then current Privacy Policy.

### Social Media

Our website includes social media tools, such as the Facebook Like button, share this button.  These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our sites, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. The social media tools are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Websites. Your interactions with these features are governed by the Privacy Policy and other relevant policies of the companies providing them.

### Products

Use of any of the products are governed by the relevant terms and conditions for the product or service.

Except as required by the Australian Consumer Law, Reckon provides the products to you on an "as is" basis and without any representations by Reckon or any of its authorised distributors regarding the use, performance or results of the use, of the products.

### Membership Reckon Community and other discussion forums

In order to be able to post information in Reckon Community or any of the discussion forums, you must become a member. To become a member, you must complete your registration details in the manner described on the website. Membership is free but non-transferable.

We reserve the right to terminate your membership at any time if you breach these terms and conditions.

If you are not a member, you are entitled to access the discussion forum for reading purposes only. Persons in this category are described as "guests".

Membership of the discussion forum is only open to you if you are 18 years old or over. If you are under 18 years of age you must not register as a member of the discussion forum.

### Members' obligations

By registering as a member of any discussion forum or accessing any discussion forum as a guest, you agree to abide by the rules and guides relating to the forum, and the following terms and conditions:

  * you acknowledge that any information or material submitted by you to the discussion forum is and will be treated by us as non-confidential and non-proprietary and we may use such material without restriction and subject to our Privacy Policy (which can be viewed on our website);
  * when you submit material to the discussion forum, you assign all copyright which subsists in such material to us;
  * you are responsible for protecting the confidentiality of your password;
  * you will not post or transmit any material or information which is offensive, defamatory, obscene, unlawful, vulgar, harmful, threatening, abusive, harassing or ethnically objectionable;
  * you agree not to disrupt the flow of dialogue or otherwise act in a manner which negatively affects other members;
  * you agree not to impersonate any other person;
  * you agree to provide current, accurate and up-to-date information about yourself as required under these terms and conditions;
  * you agree not to post or transmit any unsolicited advertising or promotional materials;
  * any material which you post may be removed by us from the discussion forum without notice at any time;
  * you will not post or transmit any material in which the copyright is owned by another person or entity and you warrant that all material posted is your original work and not sourced from any third party;
  * you will not post any material which contains viruses or other computer codes, files or programs which are designed to limit or destroy the functionality of other computer software or hardware;
  * you accept that any material or information provided by you may be posted in the discussion forum for any other members or guests to read;
  * all information provided by us in our discussion forum is provided in good faith. You accept that any information provided by us is general information and is not in the nature of advice. We derive our information from sources which we believe to be accurate and up to date as at the date of publication and we reserve the right to update this information at any time;
  * we do not make any representations or warranties that the information we provide in the discussion forum is reliable, accurate or complete or that your access to the discussion forums will be uninterrupted, timely or secure. 
  * except as required by the Australian Consumer Law, we are not liable for any loss resulting from any action taken or reliance made by you on any information or material posted by us. You should make your own inquiries and seek independent advice from relevant industry professionals before acting or relying on any information or material which appears in the discussion forum;
  * we do not accept any liability for the accuracy or content of any material posted by other members of the discussion forum. We are not liable for any loss resulting from any action taken or reliance made by you on any information or material posted by another member;
  * we do not accept any responsibility or liability for any information or material which you submit to the discussion forum, nor do we accept any responsibility for any use or misuse which you or any other members or guests make of information or material which you submit to the discussion forum;
  * we do not warrant that we will respond to questions or comments submitted by you to our discussion forums;
  * If you download any material from the discussion forum, you acknowledge that we are not liable to you for any loss or damage, however caused, arising from the downloading or subsequent use of the downloaded material. You may not adapt, reproduce, store, distribute, transmit, print, display, publish or create derivative works from any downloaded material. In addition, you may not commercialise any information, products or services from the downloaded material.

### Your posts & Disclaimer

We will correct or delete any information you have posted on the websites if you so request in accordance with Reckon’s Privacy Policy

_Disclaimer:_ We do not warrant that any material you submit to the discussion forum will be protected against loss, misuse or alteration by third parties. We do not warrant that we will post your information or material in the discussion forum. If we elect in our sole discretion to post your information or material in the discussion forum, we do not warrant that the material or information you submit will be posted within a certain timeframe.

### Third party products and online services

The website and products may contain access to, or features that interface with, third party products and online services ("Third Party Online Services"). Where Third Party Online Services are available, separate terms and conditions with the provider of the Third Party Online Services may apply. Charges may apply for the use of Third Party Online Services including the cost of internet access. Except as required by the Consumer Guarantees, access to Third Party Online Services may be withdrawn by Reckon at any time. Reckon does not make any recommendations in relation to the Third Party Online Services or accept any liability or responsibility for any loss or damage relating to the Third Party Online Services except as required by the Consumer Guarantees.  Reckon not provide financial, accounting, taxation, superannuation, wealth management or financial product advice.:

The information contained in the website, including the discussion forums or the products may contain features designed to assist you in complying with the requirements of the relevant legislation. You acknowledge that Reckon is not engaged in rendering legal, accounting or other professional services and nothing in the website, discussion forums or any of the products constitutes taxation, financial, wealth management, superannuation or other professional advice in relation to these matters. The help contained in the Software is not a substitute for obtaining the appropriate independent professional advice. Legal, accounting or other relevant professional advice should be obtained before taking any action in reliance on any of the products or services or what is produced by the or anything on the website the Software or what is produced by you using the Software.

### Reckon has no responsibility for recommendations 

Except as required by the Australian Consumer Law, Reckon, its employees, agents, contractors and the authors disclaim any and all liability and responsibility to any person, whether a user of the website, the discussion forums or the products, in respect of anything (including, without limitation, any error in or omission from the website or products) and of the consequences of any actions taken or omitted to be taken in reliance, whether wholly or partially, upon all or any part of the content, recommendations or help contained in this website or the products.

### Corruption of Data and on-line access 

Except as required by the Australian Consumer Law, Reckon and its authorised distributors disclaim all liability for any corruption of data, inability to access data, loss of data, breach of privacy, or downtime as a result of or arising from the use of any online link available between the website or the products and another server including without limitation in connection with any online Services. 

### Confidentiality

While Reckon uses its best endeavours to ensure that your information remains confidential (including the use of advanced encryption technology), the internet is not completely secure and there remains a possibility that information you provide could be intercepted by unauthorised persons. 

By accessing our site, you accept the terms of our privacy statement, which are incorporated herein.

### Trademark

Reckon R logos, Reckon Online, Online logo, Reckon Accounts, Advantage logo, Reckon Advantage are trademarks of Reckon Limited (“Reckon”).

### Copyright

You agree not to infringe Reckon’s or any third party’s copyright or any other intellectual property rights or common law rights in any of the material on the website or the products, for example you will not copy, down load, re-transmit or disseminate any of the copyrighted material (except where this is expressly permitted by Reckon). You also agree not to infringe any trademark of Reckon or a third party which appears on the Reckon site. 

### Advertisers, sponsors and links to other sites

By accessing the website it may be possible to link to other sites. Reckon is not responsible in any way for the content or information that may be available or accessed via the website is the sole responsibility of the relevant advertiser or sponsor.

### Passwords, access numbers and account numbers

On registration as a user with Reckon for a particular product you may be provided with a confidential password, access number and/or account number. It is your responsibility to keep these confidential and to notify Reckon as soon as you are aware that any of these have been accessed by unauthorised persons. If you give any of these access tools to other persons it is your responsibility for any charges or other liability that may arise from those persons having access. 

### Reckon E*TRADE

The Reckon E*TRADE service is provided solely by ETRADE AUSTRALIA SECURITIES LIMITED (E*TRADE Australia) ACN 078 174 973, AFSL No. 238277, of Level 1, 10 Bridge Street, Sydney NSW 2000a participant of the Australian Stock Exchange Limited Group, under an agreement between E*TRADE Australia and Reckon Investment Centre Limited ("RIC"). When referring you to E*TRADE Australia, a portion of the brokerage fees paid by you to E*TRADE Australia will be rebated to RIC as a commission. RIC may receive between 12% to 18% of the brokerage payable to E*TRADE Australia plus a trailing commission. To the extent permitted by the Australian Consumer law: (a) neither RIC or Reckon and its related bodies corporate have any legal liability to you in respect of the Reckon E*TRADE service and the activities and service of E*TRADE Australia and its related bodies corporate; and (b) E*TRADE Australia and its related bodies corporate have no legal liability to you in respect of the activities and services of RIC or Reckon and its related bodies corporate.

### Traffic flow

Response times and the ability to effect an on-line transaction vary with user demand. You agree not to hold Reckon (or, where applicable, any third party service provider) responsible for any inability to make an on-line transaction to the extent permitted by Australian Consumer Law.

### Obligation to pay all relevant subscription and user fees

You agree to pay all subscription, service and user fees which may be levied by Reckon for accessing its site or using the products. These charges may be varied from time to time. It is your responsibility to inform yourself of the charges which are applicable from time to time. This may either be done by accessing the information through the website or telephoning Reckon's support service.

### Limitation of liability

This clause is subject the Australian Consumer Law as amended from time to time, or other similar legislation of a state or territory of Australia.  
In Australia, our products come with guarantees that cannot be excluded under the Australian Consumer Law.  You are entitled to a replacement or refund for a major failure and compensation for any other reasonably foreseeable loss or damage.  You are also entitled to have the products repaired or replaced, or service resupplied in the case of a service, if the goods fail to be of acceptable quality and the failure does not amount to a major failure.

To the extent permitted by the Australian Consumer Law Reckon (and any third party service provider): (a) expressly exclude all implied warranties whether as to merchantability, fitness for particular purpose, or otherwise; and (b) exclude all guarantees, conditions, warranties and rights that may be implied into this agreement or imposed by law. 

The liability of Reckon (and, where applicable, a third party service provider such as a bank or financial institution) is limited (at the option of Reckon or the relevant third party service provider) to either providing the service again or paying for the costs of the service to be provided again unless otherwise required by Australian Consumer Law.

Except to the extent required by the Australian Consumer Law, neither Reckon, or where applicable, a third party service provider, shall be liable for any consequential, special, consequential, economic or indirect loss that may be occasioned by you accessing the website or using the products; and Reckon's maximum liability for damages arising in connection with you accessing website or the products.

### Accredited trainers and Professional Partners

The list of independent parties contained in Support: Training and Accounting Support section of this website is a list of independent parties who have indicated their preparedness to provide after-sales service, in respect of Reckon products Reckon Ltd does not and cannot warrant the services, the quality nor their suitability for the purpose of the services provided by the listed independent parties. It is the sole responsibility of the purchaser to make the appropriate enquires and satisfy themselves as to the quality, suitability and price competitiveness of any party they may subsequently choose to assist with them in the establishment and use of their services.

The use by the independent parties of any of the Reckon trademarks or logos and advertising material should not be construed as the endorsement of quality, suitability or price competitiveness of the service of the independent parties. There is neither a relationship of agency, partnership, joint venture nor any other association between Reckon/ and the independent party. The independent parties pay annual and other fees to Reckon/.

### Jurisdiction

You agree that the terms of this Agreement are to be governed by the laws applicable from time to time in the State of New South Wales, Australia.

### Enforceabilty

If for any reason any provision of this Agreement is rendered void or unenforceable at law, then this Agreement is to be read as if that particular term or provision had not been included.

## Reckon Accounts Hosted and Reckon One Services – Data Location, Security and Availability 

###  Data Centre 

Reckon Accounts Hosted and Reckon One data is located in datacentres operated by Amazon Web Services (AWS). AWS datacentres comply with many recognised international and national standards including PCI DSS Level 1, ISO 27001 and ISO 9001. Please visit the [AWS compliance ](https://aws.amazon.com/compliance/) page for further information.

###  Data Storage Location 

All Reckon Accounts Hosted and Reckon One servers are specifically located within Australia in the AWS Asia Pacific (Sydney) Region. The data stored in this region does not get transmitted to; or stored in any other AWS region. Inside the Sydney Region, we use multiple physical datacentres, these are referred to as availability zones. We have business continuity and disaster recovery mechanisms in place that allow for one of these availability zones to fail. 

For New Zealand clients, the New Zealand Inland Revenue Department has granted Reckon approval to hold records in Australia. . 

###  Backups 

We provide tools and facilities for Reckon Accounts Hosted customers to perform their own file level backups. While Reckon maintains disaster recovery backups for Reckon Accounts Hosted and Reckon One solutions, Reckon Accounts Hosted customers who fail to maintain their own backups risk losing their financial records. 

###  Encryption 

All Data is encrypted in transit to and from the Reckon Accounts Hosted and Reckon One Servers using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) certification provided by the industry leading certificate issuer Thawte.
